# **BANOBE PASCAL**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

HTML / CSS / SASS

JavaScript / ES6 / ES7

Node.js / Express

React.js / React-Hooks

Redux / MobX / Context

SQL / NOSQL

Git / Github

CI / CD

Bash / Shell CLI

Linux / Windows

**Bug Reports** 

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Self starter

Team player

Flexible & adaptable

Good Communication

Problem solving

#### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name: Banobe Pascal

Mobile: +256 706 537 427

Email: <u>banobepascal@gmail.com</u>

Portfolio: <u>devpascal.netlify.app</u>

Github: aithub.com/banobepascal

<u>Linkedin.com/in/banobe-pascal-36196519a</u>

#### **PROFILE**

I'm Banobe Pascal a dedicated and efficient full stack developer with experience in JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, React-Redux, MobX and SQL/NoSQL. I am very passionate about problem-solving, satisfying the users with the best experience as well as the best delivery service. I possess strong attention to detail, well-developed time management skills, and the ability to complete all projects within schedule and in a timely manner.

#### **OBJECTIVE**

To be able use my expert problem solving and communication skills to work with teams and companies developing products and tools people love to use.

## **KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCES**

- Experience of working through all stages of a development project.
- Understanding of Object Oriented Programming.
- Ability to manage own projects and portfolio.
- Good administration and organizational skills.
- A strong understanding of professional software development practices.
- Able to communicate complex issues to a large range of stakeholders at all levels.
- Have exposure to requirements definition and concept of workflow / reporting.
- Integration of third party APIs to front-end and back-end.
- Knowledge of differing methodologies i.e. Agile and Scrum.
- Familiarity with CI/CD technologies and workflow (TravisCI, Code Climate).
- Knowledge of unit and integration testing with Mocha / Chai and Jest.
   Experience in pair programming and team work at all levels.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Higher diploma in Software Engineering** - June 2018 - present. (Aptech Computer Education, Uganda)

# Build web apps with ReactJS

(OpenClassrooms)

#### Learn Programming With JavaScript

(OpenClassrooms)

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Freelance software developer - Jan 2020 - Present.

Andela, Kigali (Bootcamp) - Sept 2019 - Oct 2019.

#### **RECENT WORK AND PROJECTS**

# MANSA: https://github.com/banobepascal/Mansa-Frontend

An online ecommerce web app for shopping a variety of products and services.

- Worked together with the fellow team of Mansa to provide an MVP.
- Pair programmed with a fellow senior developer to bring up the Mansa product.
- Implemented Mobx and Concept API to handle state management of the app.
- Implemented responsive design of the app for user experience on small screens.
  Utilized: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, MobX, React-router, Firebase, Vercel.
- CROWN TRENDZZ: https://crown-trendzz.herokuapp.com

An online fashion e-commerce platform.

- Integrated Stripe API for processing credit card payments
- Implemented Firebase for authentication and firestorm as a database.
- Implemented best coding practices to improve project effectiveness.
  Utilized: JavaScript, React, Redux, React-router, Firebase, StripeAPI
- \_\_\_\_\_

# TEAMWORK: https://github.com/banobepascal/teamwork

An internal social network for organizations' employees. A project part of the Andela bootcamp training program.

- Designed front-end with HTML/CSS, JavaScript and fontawesome.
- Used Mocha and Chai for unit and integration testing of API.
- Applied DevOps practices i.e. CI/CD with TravisCI and Code Climate.
- Utilized: JavaScript, Nodejs, Express, PostgresQL, Mocha / Chai, TravisCl, Heroku.

**PERSONAL PORTFOLIO:** <a href="https://devpascal.netlify.app">https://devpascal.netlify.app</a>
For additional information and project links to <a href="https://devpascal.netlify.app">Github</a>